就现在怎样
What do you say now?
我不知道
I don't know.
你说你爸爸一小时内不会回来
You said your dad wouldn't be home for an hour.
没错  但你不知道
I know, but you don't know
难道你不爱我吗
Don't you love me?
当然  你知道我
Of course. You know l-
那还犹豫什么  来嘛
Then, come on. Let's do it.
好吧
All right.
-它们在哪儿  -床头柜里
- Where are they?  - Nightstand.
阁下  发动你的引擎吧
Gentlemen, start your engines.
我爱死这车啦
I so want this car!
哦天哪  你在流血
Oh, my God! You're bleeding.
小心
Look out!
他们又在扯什么谎
What lie are they telling you?
我会核对的  好的  行
I'll check on it. Okay. Yes-
快点儿  大哥
Come on.
好  谢谢
Okay, thank you.
药物今早就已寄出
Okay, pharmaceuticals were delivered this morning.
但运输公司误将装有维科丁的药箱
But Shipping accidentally sent the box with Vicodin
送到了研究室
to Research.
嗯  那还真是难办
Hmm. That's a tough one.
若我们能
If only we had some way
和那个部门协商一下就好了
to communicate with another part of the building.
16岁的孩子  机动车交通事故
Sixteen-year-old M.V.A. victim.
他由于内出血
He's been in and out of the hospital
过去三周一直进进出出医院
for three weeks with internal bleeding.
没人能找出病因所在
No one can find the cause.
车祸后内出血  哇  还真是震惊啊
Internal bleeding after a car accident. Wow, that's shocking.
让我和运输公司说  我有办法对付他们
Let me talk to Shipping. I speak their language.
已经三个星期了
It's been three weeks-
你的医院里没有我要的止痛药
Your hospital doesn't have my pain medication.
运输公司说要一个小时才到
Shipping says it's going to be an hour.
我是卡迪医生  怎么回事
This is Dr. Cuddy. What's going on?
不是车祸引起的出血
The crash didn't cause the bleed.
没错  是出血引起了车祸
Right- the bleed caused the crash.
血流到路上  车在路上打滑了
Blood got on the road, got all slippery-
谁身上带了药[毒品]
Anyone here got drugs?
她看到他流血  就分心了
She saw his blood, she got distracted,
还把他爸爸的保时捷撞毁了
and she crashed his dad's Porsche.
他爸爸会很高兴的
Dad'll love that.
-他...  -别再说了
- He was-  - Don't talk.
要等一个小时
It's gonna be an hour.
谢天谢地  你大局在握
Thank God you took control.
如果你等不了一个小时
If you can't wait one hour to get-
那孩子患有溶血性贫血
Kid's got hemolytic anemia.
孩子  多大
Kid? How old?
肯定是遗传  命不久矣
He must have inherited it. He's gonna die.
请节哀
My condolences.
不是遗传
Wasn't inherited.
不是红细胞的问题
The problem's outside the red blood cells.
这不可能
This is impossible.
16岁的孩子 不可能得溶血性贫血
A 16-year-old does not get hemolytic anemia.
把病历还给她
Give her back the file.
你有更重要的事情要处理  如帮我找药
You have bigger problems to tend to, like my meds.
间接胆红素偏高  血清结合珠蛋白水平偏低
Elevated indirect bilirubin, low serum haptoglobin-
-他有脑膜炎  -没有
- He's got meningitis. - Uh, no.
-人工心脏瓣膜  -没有
- Artificial heart valve. - No.
叫大伙儿到我办公室集合
Get everyone in my office.
若不尽快找出他红细胞溶解的原因
Kid's gonna be dead in a matter of days...
几天之内就会没命
if we don't figure out why his red blood cells are disintegrating.
说说你们的鉴别诊断吧  同志们
So, differential diagnosis, people.
不是环境所致
Well, it's not environmental.
他爸爸雇了清洁工清理房子
Dad hired a company to clean the house.
女佣洗了所有的衣物
Maid washed all the clothes...
还买了低过敏性床单和枕头
and bought hypoallergenic sheets and pillows.
-要重新检查一下吗  -没必要
- You want us to recheck?  - No.
若和环境有关  在这儿他该好转才是
If it's environmental, he'll get better just from staying here.
有可能是感染
It could be an infection.
没发烧  白细胞也没增加
No fever. No white count.
但他的体温有99.2[华氏]
Well, he's 99.2.
只比正常体温高一点点
Barely above normal.
但还是高了  他的身体在对什么起反应
But above. His body's reacting to something.
若是红斑狼疮的话  就能解释
We could account for the lack
为什么没发烧  白细胞也没增加了
of fever and white count if it's lupus.
吸毒也可以出现与红斑狼疮类似的症状
Drugs will fit just as much as lupus.
冰毒会引起溶血性贫血
Meth will cause hemolytic anemia.
要大量冰毒才行
A lot of meth.
而且他看起来也不像这种人
Also doesn't exactly seem like the type.
因为他爸爸开的是保时捷吗
Because his dad drives a Porsche?
富家子弟也和穷人的孩子一样吸毒
Rich kids do drugs just like poor kids.
没想冒犯你
Didn't mean to offend you.
好啦  也就是说病因可能是
Okay.! So it's
感染  红斑狼疮  毒品或癌症
infection, lupus, drugs or cancer.
癌症
Cancer?
为什么不可能  很棒的会议
Why not? Great meeting.
会议结束前  不需要再缩小可能性吗
Shouldn't we narrow it down before we finish?
我的腿只能坚持到十一点一刻
My leg gave us till 11:15.
我去和威尔森讨论淋巴瘤的可能性
I'll talk to Wilson about lymphoma,
做抗核抗体检查  看是否是红斑狼疮
A.N.A. for lupus,
还有放射免疫检验  检查毒品
radioimmunoassay for drugs,
你们就去检查所有你们认为可能的病因
and you test for whatever you thought it was.
我和药剂师有个约会
I've got a date with the pharmacist.
这个已经解决了  还有
That's already done, and-
快点  快快快
Come on! Come on, come on, come on.
就是这个
Yeah.
稍等一下
Excuse me.
知不知道  止痛的方法可不止这一个
You know, there are other ways to manage pain.
比如呢  大笑  冥想
Like what? Laughter? Meditation?
还是有人能治好我的第三脉轮
Got a guy that can fix my third chakra?
你已经上瘾了
You're addicted.
靠止痛药过活才叫上瘾
If the pills ran my life, I'd agree with you,
但是我的腿让我无法专心做事
but it's my leg that's busy calendaring what I can't do.
你这是否认期的表现
You're in denial.
是啊  我的腿从来没有梗死过
Right. I never had an infarction in my leg.
肌肉没坏死  神经也没受损
No dead muscle, no nerve damage.
甚至一点都不疼  事实上像在挠痒
Doesn't even hurt. Actually, it kinda tickles.
而小鸡比小狗更擅长这个
And chicks dig this... better than a puppy.
不只是你腿的问题  是你想兴奋起来
It's not just your leg. You wanna get high.
你每天用多少  八十毫克吗
You're doing, what, 80 milligrams a day?
没有  那太多了
No. That's way too much.
节制是关键  除非疼痛折磨
Moderation is the key. Unless there's pain.
现在的剂量是我雇你时的两倍了
It's double what you were taking when I hired you.
因为你比那时候烦人两倍
'Cause you're twice as annoying.
我不可能总是包庇你
I can't always be here to protect you.
病人在议论  医生也在议论
Patients talk. Doctors talk.
议论你的屁屁最近又翘了多少
About how big your ass has gotten lately?
没谈论我  我申辩
Not me. I defend it.
你东山再起了
You got back.
没止痛药你一星期都忍受不了
You can't go a week without the drugs.
是的  我也不想
No, I don't wanna go without the drugs.
-腿会疼  -不  是你做不到
- It'll hurt.  - No, you can't.
如果你是停用止疼药  你会疼
If you're just getting off pain medication, it will hurt.
你会很难受  但你可以挺过去
You won't be having a great time, but you'll make it.
而若是戒毒的话  你会寒颤  恶心
If you're detoxing, you'll have chills, nausea.
你的疼痛会是现在的五倍  甚至十倍
Your pain will magnify five, ten times.
那时你就熬不过去了
You won't make it.
唉  我看我们没机会知道了
Well, I guess we'll never know.
如果你能坚持一星期不嗑药的话
I'll give you a week off clinic duty
你一星期不用坐门诊
if you can go a week without narcotics.
我才不干呢  我爱门诊
No way. I love the clinic.
你是爱止痛药  两星期
You love the pills. Two weeks.
止痛药不会让我兴奋  是让我恢复正常
The pills don't make me high. They make me neutral.
一个月
A month.
你得逞了  女士
You're on, mister.
他的病是毒品引起的吗
Drugs could cause this?
可卡因和冰毒对血液系统影响非常严重
Cocaine and meth are very hard on the blood system.
他有什么古怪行为吗
Has he had any erratic behavior?
没有  但是
No, but-
她在戒毒中  到第九级了
She was in rehab in the ninth grade.
现在应该已经戒清了  但...
She's supposedly clean now, but-
她明显很关心他
She obviously cares for him.
是吗  她关心的是那辆车
Yeah, what she cared about was the car.
那是给我妻子的周年礼物
Anniversary present for my wife.
我们开着它到北方去看叶子变化
We drove it up north to watch the leaves change.
一年后她就死了
She was dead a year later.
-是癌症  -很抱歉
- Cancer.  - I'm sorry.
福斯特先生  我们会给凯斯做毒品检测
Mr. Foster, we're gonna test Keith for drugs.
我  我不吸毒的
I- I don't do drugs.
并不是我们不相信你  而是
It's not that we don't trust you, but-
从他的头发中可以检测出
His hair will tell us any drugs
他在过去两个月之内服用过的任何毒品
he's taken over the past 60 days.
其原理有点类似树上的年轮
It's kind of like rings on a tree.
阴性
Negative.
-你有没有患过什么重病  -没有
- Have you been sick? - No, nothing.
有没有出过国
Have you been out of the country?
我们去过中国  但离开前我们都打过疫苗
We went to China, but we got all our shots before we left.
有可能是感染
It could be an infection.
我们将对他进行镓扫描   以防万一
We're going to give him a gallium scan just to be safe.
我们将放射性同位素注射进他的血流中
We inject a radioactive isotope into his bloodstream,
然后检查  看他的体内有没有炎症
and we check to see if there's inflammation anywhere in the body.
他有没有提过关节痛
Has he ever complained of any joint pain?
对光敏感  或者出疹子
Sensitivity to light? Rashes?
没有  从没说过
No, no. Nothing.
有亲戚得过红斑狼疮吗
Any relatives who've ever been diagnosed with lupus?
我都不知道这是什么病
I don't even know what that is.
简单说  就是身体自身过敏
In simple terms, the body becomes allergic to itself.
免疫系统攻击并消灭
The immune system attacks
循环系统中健康的细胞
healthy cells in the circulatory system and destroys them.
能治疗吗
Would it be treatable?
可以进行控制
It can be manageable.
我们能检查他的抗体
We can test for the antibodies.
95%的红斑狼疮患者的抗核抗体都呈阳性
Ninety-five percent of patients with lupus have positive A.N.A.
没有变浑浊  是阴性
Not cloudy. Negative.
那么有没有挫伤
What about bruising?
他从未说过腋下或腹股沟处有压痛吗
Never complained of tenderness under his arms or his groin?
就算有  恐怕他也不会告诉我
I'm not sure he'd tell me if he did.
我想我都不知道他生活是怎样的
I guess I don't really know what's going on in his life.
-他还是个青少年  -是啊
- He's a teenager. - Yeah.
你妻子患的是什么癌症呢
What type of cancer did your wife have?
胰腺癌
Pancreatic.
我们担心他的淋巴结有问题
It's his lymph nodes we're concerned about.
我们将做活检  看是否是淋巴瘤
We're going to do a biopsy to check for lymphoma.
-有感觉吗  -没有
- Can you feel this?  - No.
很好
Good.
我得了癌症  是吗
I have cancer, don't I?
我们只是在做检查
We're just testing.
那时他们也是这样对我妈妈说的
That's what they told my mom.
绝对不是癌症
Definitely not cancer.
-什么都没发现  -一无所获
- Nothing? - Nothing.
毒品检测抗核抗体检查均为阴性
Negative for drugs. A.N.A. Was negative.
镓扫描也没什么可疑迹象
Gallium scan was clear.
是的  我知道一无所获是什么意思
Yeah, I got that from the "Nothing."
-他的血球容量是多少  -13
- Where's his hematocrit?  - Thirteen.
如果再降低  他的红细胞
Drops any lower, he's not gonna have
将不足以携带足够的氧气供给全身
enough red blood cells to bring oxygen to his body.
到时他的肺部功能正常  但他会窒息而死
He'll suffocate with his lungs working perfectly.
你还好吗
You okay?
不好意思  有人在吗  救命
Excuse me, someone? Help. Please!
这个将死的娃还挺有礼貌
Polite for a dying kid.
已经坚持多久了
How long has it been?
我好着呢
I'm fine.
-我眼睛上面有东西  -哪只眼睛
- There's something in my eye. Up at the top. - Which eye?
这只  怎么回事
This one. What's happening?
没事的  向下看
It's all right. Just look down for me.
很干净  没有异物
It's clear. There's nothing in it.
-越来越糟了  -有模糊感还是
- It's getting worse. - Is it fuzzy or-
不是  完全变黑了
No, it's dark.
我看不见了
I can't see.
左眼视网膜血栓
It's a retinal clot in the left eye.
华法林可以溶解血栓  恢复视力
Coumadin would dissolve the clot, fix his eyesight.
现在不能使用抗凝血剂  他有内出血
You can't use blood thinners. He's got internal bleeding.
可以恢复视力  但会毁了其他的一切
Fix the eye, you'd kill everything else.
同样的原因  也不能手术
Surgery's out for the same reason.
我们有两个小时的时间解决这个问题
We have two hours to figure this out.
要是无法恢复血流量  他的眼睛就保不住了
Either we restore the blood flow, or he loses the eye.
别管眼睛了
Forget the eye.
告诉他用另一只眼睛去寻找光明
Tell him to use the other one to look on the bright side.
血栓里面暗藏玄机
The clot tells us something.
能帮助我们解开谜团
Could help us figure out what he has,
或许他还有一线生机
which could mean he gets to live.
开始鉴别诊断  同志们
Differential diagnosis, people.
内出血病人怎么会突发血栓
How does internal bleeding suddenly start clotting?
这不可能  这是两个相反的过程
It makes no sense. They're opposing processes.
红斑狼疮就有可能
It can happen in lupus.
血小板数量增多会导致血栓形成
Increased platelet count can cause blood clots.
抗核抗体检测呈阴性  不是红斑狼疮
A.N.A. was negative. It's not lupus.
在理
This is true.
可是为什么会从你嘴里说出来
But why are you the one saying it?
你跑这儿干嘛
What are you doing here?
不是已经排除癌症了吗
I thought we'd ruled out cancer.
一个人没意思
I was lonely.
看卡迪去  她需要朋友
Well, go see Cuddy. She needs a friend.
真有意思  她也这么说你
That's funny. She said you might need one.
原来是这么回事
That's why you're here.
她派你来监视我
She wants you to keep an eye on me.
防止我作弊
Make sure I don't cheat.
不是  我是来看着你
No, I wanted to make sure
防止你乱开炮
you don't start firing shots from the clock tower.
我没事
I'm fine-
什么情况
What's going on?
他已经一天多没吃维科丁
He hasn't had vicodin in over a day.
你腿疼吗
Does your leg hurt?
挨一枪你就明白了
You ever been shot?
这会有副作用
There's gonna be side effects.
失眠  抑郁  心动过速
Insomnia, depression, tachycardia.
戒断症状  用错对象了
Withdrawal symptoms. Not applicable.
对我唯一的副作用就是
The only side effects I'm gonna have
一点疼痛和三十天的自由
are some pain and 30 days of freedom.
这里就我一个人关心那个将死的孩子吗
Am I the only one who's concerned about a dying kid?
如果不是红斑狼疮  那是什么
If it's not lupus, what else?
最有可能导致血栓的是
Most likely candidate for throwing a clot
感染和癌症
is infection or cancer.
活检结果确定了两次  不是癌症
Checked the biopsy twice. It's not cancer.
不是感染  镓扫描没发现异常
It's not an infection. Gallium scan didn't reveal anything.
好吧  哪里镓扫描无法覆盖
Okay. What hides from a Gallium scan?
心脏
Cardiac.
没错  血栓脱落后通过动脉
Right. Clot flicks off, travels through the arteries,
到达眼部并滞留下来
then gets backed up in the eye.
抱歉  我刚才走神了  说到哪里
I'm sorry. I wasn't paying attention. What happened?
他的心脏上有感染
It's an infection in his heart.
太好了
Great.
做超声心动图
Echocardiogram for the heart
立即静脉注射抗生素
and I.V. antibiotics for the infection, stat.
今天是我生日吗
Is it my birthday?
我不孤独  只是腿疼而已
I'm not lonely. My leg hurts.
她是正经的按摩师
She's a real masseuse.
她一小时要价至少500美金
She's $500 an hour, minimum.
长的性感就一定是妓女吗
She's hot, so she's a hooker?
你这是哪门子的歪理
What kind of pathetic logic is that?
因为高中从来没爽过
The envious, jealous,
导致妒火攻心的歪理  看不出来吗
l-never-got-any-in-high-school kind of logic. Hello!
她是合法执业按摩师
She's a legitimate masseuse.
拜托别这样
Come on.
天哪  她美呆了
God! She's beautiful.
就因为她漂亮  我就该招呼她
Because she's beautiful, I should do it?
你又是哪门子的歪理
What kind of pathetic logic is that?
身为有妇之夫围在城里导致妒火攻心的歪理
The envious, jealous, I'm-married-and-l-can't-do-anything logic.
你好
Hello.
是这样
Hi. Uh, listen,
我相信你不管干什么都是一把好手  但
I'm sure you're really good at whatever it is you do, but-
-把手给我[西语]  -啥
-Deme su mano. -Huh?
嘿  别  放开我的手
Hey, no, no. Let go of my hand.
-别这样  -她不懂英语
- Come on. - She doesn't speak English.
老天爷
Oh, my God.
爽[西语]
Bueno.
脱掉衣服
Take off your clothes.
不喜欢吃沙拉酱肉吗
Not a fan of the stroganoff?
-我不饿  -抗生素可能引起反胃
-I'm not hungry. -Well, the antibiotics can cause nausea.
吃的也一样
So can the food.
你不是应该检查我的眼睛吗
Shouldn't you be looking at my eye?
这个血栓并不致命
The blood clot isn't life-threatening.
我们更关注你的根本病因
We're focusing on figuring out the cause of your problems.
也就是说我会永久失明  是吗
So the- so the blindness will be permanent, won't it?
-谢谢  -再见
- Thank you. - Bye.
我做了个按摩
I had a massage.
看起来像是你做了按摩师  消痛吗
Looks like you had a masseuse. Help the pain?
-我挺好的  -我知道
- I'm fine. - I know.
那孩子心超正常
Kid's echo was normal.
心脏瓣膜上无赘生物
No signs of any vegetations on heart valves.
你怎么说我都能驳倒的
Never met a diagnostic study I couldn't refute.
抗生素没有效果
And the antibiotics aren't doing anything.
剂量加倍  给到70毫克
So double the dosage. 70 milligrams.
那他的肾脏肯定要报销
That'll box his kidneys for sure.
你说的对  那就保住肾脏
Oh, you're right. Save the kidney.
接受移植的那个人肯定会感激不尽的
The guy we transplant it into will be grateful.
还有我有办法治疗他的眼睛
Also, I have an idea for his eye.
他的眼睛已经无可挽回了
Nothing we can do about his eye.
-他视网膜上有血栓  -别琢磨了
- He's got a clot in the retina - Put it in a memo.
如果我们从眼内
If we remove some of the liquid
抽出些玻璃状液
from the eye itself, the vitreous humour,
也许能在视网膜动脉周边腾出空间
it might make some extra room around the retinal artery.
如果动脉扩张  血栓或许能自行游离开
If the artery expands, the clot might move on its own.
挺有创意
That's very creative.
你原来怎么没提
Why didn't you mention this before?
先前没想到
I didn't think of it before.
你应该想到的
You should've.
肯定会疼
This is going to hurt.
你的眼部已经麻痹了  只会有点压迫感
Your eye is numb. You'll only feel pressure.
等一小会
Give it a minute.
我能看到了
I can see.
我能看到你了
I can see you.
我听说了  恭喜
I heard. Congratulations.
别  我已经两天没刷牙了
Don't. I haven't brushed my teeth in two days.
我很害怕  怕他们查不出你的病因
I'm so scared they're not gonna find out what's wrong with you.
没什么大不了的  我很好
No biggie. I'm fine.
我感觉糟透了  都是我的错
I feel so bad about all this. It's all my fault.
不  不是这样的
No. No, it's not.
但你爸爸  他恨我
But your father- he hates me.
他只是因为车的事情生气
He's just pissed about his car.
救命  救命  救命
Help! Help! Help!
什么情况
What's wrong?
谷草转氨酶水平859  转危重症病房
A.S.T. is 859. We're getting him to the I.C.U.
谷丙转氨酶和谷氨酰转肽酶也岌岌可危
A.L.T. and G.G.T. are in the tank.
-抗生素  -不可能是抗生素引起的
- Our antibiotics - would not have caused this.
她肯定给他毒品了
She must have given him drugs!
-我没有  -与毒品无关
- I wouldn't do that! - It's not drugs!
-他的肝脏在衰竭  -什么
- His liver is shutting down. - What?
那是什么意思
What does that mean?
说明他已经痊愈  可以回家了
It means he's all better. He's ready to go home.
-什么  -那你以为是什么意思
- What? - What do you think it means?
人没有肝就无法存活  他要死了
You can't live without a liver. He's dying.
-你有什么毛病  -瘸腿  你呢
- What is your problem? - Bum leg. What's yours?
没时间纠缠这些了  快进去
Hey, we don't have time for this. Let's go.
他儿子生命垂危  你还讽刺他
His son's dying, and you're mocking him?
他的问题太蠢了
It was a dumb question.
不是这样
No, it wasn't.
你说的对  那不蠢
You're right. It wasn't.
证明卡迪错了就有这么重要吗
Is proving Cuddy wrong worth all this?
豪斯压根就不应该待在医院
You know, House shouldn't even be here.
就因为他出言不逊
Because he said something inappropriate?
要是每次如此都要撵他回家
If we sent him home every time he did that,
那这个办公室早就关门大吉了
we wouldn't need this office.
他很痛苦
He's in pain.
他要做到什么地步才能激怒你们
What does the man have to do to piss you off?
他已经70多小时没吃止痛片了
He's been without pain relief for over 70 hours.
说的就是这个
Exactly!
他在戒毒  你们看不出来他已经失去理智了吗
He's detoxing. Can't you see he's out of his mind?
他们也是这么说曼森的[摇滚歌手]
That's what they said about Manson.
你们是想接着聊我的八卦
Do you wanna continue talking about me,
还是讨论肝衰竭表明的问题呢
or should we discuss what the liver damage tells us?
我出生在伊利诺伊的一个小木屋里
I was born in a log cabin in Illinois-
溶血性贫血不会导致肝衰竭
Hemolytic anemia doesn't cause liver damage.
加上他在咯血
Add the fact he's coughing blood,
已经有三条线索表明这是红斑狼疮
you've got three of the indicators of organ-threatening lupus.
红斑狼疮不会发展这么快
It's moving too fast.
可能是戊型肝炎
Could be hepatitis "E."
至今只发现过一例源于美国的戊型肝炎
There's only been one case of hep "E" originating in the U.S.
据记载
Since his history says
他去年曾四次出入境
he's been in and out of the country four times in the last year.
你真的认为他得了戊型肝炎
You really think he's got hep "E"?
不是  我觉得红斑狼疮可能性更大些
No. I think lupus is way more likely.
好  给他静脉注射环磷酰胺  去血浆
All right, then let's start him on I.V. Cytoxan and plasmapheresis.
不对  应该首先排除戊型肝炎
No, we should rule out hep "E."
你才说过不是戊型肝炎
You just said it wasn't hep "E."
我只是说红斑狼疮可能性更大些
I said lupus is way more likely,
但如果他得的是戊型肝炎
but if we treat for lupus
而我们按红斑狼疮来治疗
and it is hep "E"-
-那他就完蛋了  -没错
- He's toast. - Exactly.
但戊型肝炎尚无有效的治疗方案
But there isn't a treatment for hepatitis "E."
要么自行恢复  要么持续恶化
Either he'll get better on his own or he'll continue to deteriorate.
是啊  我在医学院里也学过
Yeah. I went to medical school too.
使用甲强龙
Start him on solumedrol.
如果是戊型肝炎  这么做只会恶化病情
If he's got hep "E," that's only gonna make him worse.
少用点  要掌握火候  同志们
Not as much. It's Goldilocks, people.
不能做的太过  把他弄死
Won't hurt him so much that it'll kill him,
也不能小到没有效果
and it won't hurt him so little that we can't tell.
要刚刚好
It'll hurt him... just right.
如果不起作用
And if it does nothing-
我们就可以排除戊型肝炎
we'll know it's not hep "E"
而以狼疮来治疗
and can start treating for lupus.
那你们喝点水  看着我干吧
Now watch me do it while drinking a glass of water.
我们该跟他爸说什么
What do we tell the dad?
"我们认为您的孩子有狼疮
"We think your kid has lupus,
所以当作戊型肝炎来治疗
so we're gonna treat him for hepatitis 'E'.
而如果他得的是戊型肝炎
And, oh, yeah, if it really is hep 'E,'
我们现在用的药又无法治愈他
we're not actually giving him hep 'E ' medication.
所以无论如何他的病情只会恶化  不会改善
So it's gonna make him worse, not better."
你觉得他能接受这说法
Think he'll go for that?
-你希望我们撒谎  -没有
- So you want us to lie? - No.
-我想让你去骗他  -为什么是我
- I want you to lie. - Why me?
因为他信任你
Because he trusts you.
-这是个错误  -会被起诉的
- This is a mistake. - This is a lawsuit.
戊型肝炎只是一种可能
Hep "E" is possible.
豪斯总是耍这些花招
House always pulls these stunts,
而且通常都是对的
and he's right more often-
他延迟治疗就因为那百万分之一的机会
He's delaying treatment because of a
即便他自己都否定
one-in-a-million chance that even he doesn't think is the problem.
-我不想骗他  -那就别骗
- I don't wanna lie to him. - Then don't.
然后被炒吗
And get fired?
他才不会炒你  他爱死你了
Oh, like he's gonna fire you. He loves you.
我得做点什么
I've gotta do something.
孩子需要治疗
Kid needs treatment.
当作狼疮来治
Treat him for lupus.
这会让你被炒的
That will get you fired.
你真的认为豪斯疯了
You really think House is losing it?
是啊
Yeah.
他没疯  他知道自己在干什么
He's fine. He knows what he's doing.
好了
Okay.
我们建议使用甲强龙
We're recommending a drug called solumedrol.
治疗肝炎吗  血检显示是肝炎吗
For hepatitis? Did that show up on his blood tests?
检查结果不会百分百准确
The tests are never 100% accurate.
那其他检查结果也可能是错的
Well, then all the other tests could be wrong too.
他可能是感染或者癌症
This could still be an infection or cancer.
他最近的症状与那些病不符
They don't fit any of the most recent symptoms.
什么  只有肝炎符合吗
Well, what, just hepatitis does?
我知道  我知道你们永远不能确定
I know, I know, I know- you can never be sure.
以前温蒂住院的时候
When Wendy was in the hospital,
医生说有种激进的实验性疗法
a doctor told us there was this aggressive experimental treatment...
也许能让她多活两三年
which might extend her life by two or three years.
我们觉得  只要有一丝希望
Well, we figured if there was any hope at all that
让她多陪陪我们  都值得我们去尝试
we could have her with us a little while longer, it'd be worth it.
三周后  她就死了
Three weeks later, she was gone.
我认为不是肝炎
I don't think it's hepatitis.
我认为你儿子得了狼疮
I think your son has lupus.
我认为你骨折了
I think it's broken.
你干什么了
What did you do?
不小心把手夹车门里了
Accidentally closed the car door on it.
不可能  车门会把皮肤蹭破的
No. Door would've broken the skin.
看起来像是被某样坚硬平整的东西砸断的
This looks like something hard and smooth smashed it.
我要见我的律师
I want my lawyer.
大脑对疼痛的耐受有一个阈值
The brain has a gating mechanism for pain.
会记录下最严重的疼痛信号
Registers the most severe injury
并阻止其他疼痛信号传入大脑
and blocks out the others.
它起作用了吗
Did it work?
我的手疼得要死
Well, my hand hurts like hell.
是的  我感觉好多了
Yeah. I feel much better.
别给我上夹板
Don't splint it.
我希望下次需要止疼时
I want to be able to bang it against the wall
还能用这只手砸墙
if I need to administer another dose.
包扎一下就好
Just tape it up.
你为什么让卡梅隆骗福斯特先生
Why did you tell Cameron to lie to Mr. Foster?
-包紧点  -回答我
- Make it tight. - Answer me.
我说什么都改变不了你的看法
Nothing I can say is gonna change how you feel,
你的反应也都不会
and nothing can come out of your reaction
改变我的计划
that is gonna change what I plan to do,
所以我情愿什么都不说
so I prefer to say nothing.
这就是你所谓的"什么都不说吗"
So that was just you saying nothing.
-那人已经暴怒了  -还吓坏了
- The guy is furious. - And scared.
那你打算怎么办
So what are you gonna do?
他爸坚持当作狼疮来治疗
The father's insisting on the lupus treatment.
是的  卡梅隆跟我说过了
Yeah, Cameron told me,
我让她转告他不行
and I told her to tell him no.
你不能袖手旁观  就让那孩子死去
Well, you can't just sit back and let the kid die.
-他爸也不行  -那你计划怎样
- Neither can the father. -So that's your plan?
你要拿那孩子的命当赌注吗
You're gonna play chicken with the kid's life?
那是他爸  我会赢得很轻松
Well, he's the dad. I should win easily.
休一礼拜假吧
Take the week off.
为什么  就因为我对病人撒谎了
Why, 'cause I lied to a patient?
我冒险  有时病人会因此死亡
I take risks. Sometimes patients die.
但我不冒险会让更多病人死亡
But not taking risks causes more patients to die,
所以我想我最大的问题是
so I guess my biggest problem is
一直为自己的计算能力所苦
I've been cursed with the ability to do the math.
我告诉他我们不会作为狼疮治疗  直到
I told him that we wouldn't treat him for the lupus until-
他说什么
What'd he say?
他说他想让凯斯转院
He said he wanted to transfer Keith to another hospital.
他情况不稳定  都撑不到出门
He's not stable enough. He'd never make it through the door.
我就是这么说的
That's what I told him.
那他妥协了吧
And that's when he caved.
是啊  他同意了你的方案
Yeah. He agreed to do it your way.
二加二等于四
Two plus two equals four.
肝功结果一小时内就会出来
If it is hepatitis "E", we should see a marked decline
如果真是戊肝  肝炎指数就会明显下降
in liver function tests within the hour.
干嘛要跟我解释这个
Why bother explaining it to me?
我别无选择
It's not like I have any choice in the matter.
如果不是戊型肝炎
If there's no hep "E",
我们马上按照狼疮来治疗
we'll start treatment for lupus immediately.
-凯斯  怎么了  -怎么了
- Keith? What's wrong? - What's happening?
别这样  走开
No, get off.
凯斯  我是奇斯医生  哪里疼
Keith, it's Dr. Chase. Where does it hurt?
朱尔斯  别这样
Jules, no!
-他产生幻觉了  -是药物作用
- He's hallucinating. - Is this from the medicine?
-我们还没开始用药  -凯斯
- We haven't started the medicine. - Keith,
你在医院里  凯斯  你身上什么都没有
you're in the hospital. Keith, there's nothing on you.
-凯斯  -凯斯  凯斯  凯斯
- Hey. Hey. Keith. - Keith! Keith! Keith!
你还好吧  孩子
Hey. You okay, buddy?
我想我尿床了
Um, I think I wet the bed.
别担心  没关系  我们把你扶起来
Oh- Don't worry about it. It's fine. Let's get you up.
-天啊  -他大出血了
- Oh, God.! - He's had a major bleed.
鲜红色的  是直肠出血
Bright red blood per rectum.
我不是故意的  对不起
I didn't- I didn't mean to. I'm sorry.
他失血性休克了
He's going into hypovolemic shock.
血压60  心率140
Pressure's 60, heart rate's 140.
立刻进行血管造影术
We need an angiography, stat!
血管造影提示胃肠道大出血
Angiography revealed major upper and lower G.I. Bleeding,
严重血液动力学障碍和肝功能衰竭
severe hemodynamic compromise and liver failure.
他还产生幻觉
He's also hallucinating.
认为自己在被一个名叫朱尔斯的人折磨着
Thinks he's being tortured by someone named Jules.
幻觉是精神病的症状之一
Hallucinations are a symptom of psychosis,
这是第四个诊断指标
which is the fourth diagnostic criterion.
可以确诊为狼疮了
It's official. This is lupus.
谁是朱尔斯
Who's Jules?
病史里有提过她吗
Any mention of her in the medical history?
他幻想什么并不重要
It doesn't matter what he's hallucinating about,
重要的是产生幻觉的原因  这是狼疮
it matters why. It's lupus.
没必要发火嘛
Well, there's no need to get snippy.
这种狼疮需要很多年才会发展到这步
This kind of lupus takes years to get to this point.
-他才发病一礼拜  -是啊
- It's been a week. - Yeah.
16岁的孩子不应患有溶血性贫血
And a 16-year-old kid shouldn't have hemolytic anemia
或者七窍流血  但他有
or be bleeding out of every orifice, but he is.
我们本来有机会治疗的
We had an opportunity to treat this.
却一直绕着戊型肝炎转
Instead, we diddled around with hepatitis "E"
现在治也晚了
and now it's too late.
他需要换肝  我们搞砸了
He needs a new liver. We screwed up.
你是说我搞砸了
You're saying I screwed up.
-是的  -那你干嘛不直接说出来
- Yes. - Then why don't you just say that?
你这是在责怪她吗
You gonna blame this on her?
你同意当做戊型肝炎治疗的建议吗
Did you agree with my recommendation to treat for hep "E"?
-我不同意  -她已经说得很清楚了
- No, I didn't. - And she made herself quite clear.
那她还对那个父亲撒谎
And then she went and lied to the father.
这才是你们生气的原因
That's why you're angry.
我那是信任你
Yeah. I trusted you.
你总是信任我  这就大错特错了
You always trust me. That's a big mistake.
狼疮的诊断是错的
Lupus is a bad diagnosis.
这是目前最合理的诊断了
It's the best diagnosis we've got.
但并不意味它就是对的
That doesn't make it good.
没错  但这给了孩子唯一的生存机会
No. It just makes it this kid's only chance to live.
把他列入移植等待名单
Put him on the transplant list.
确保卡迪知道此事
And make sure Cuddy knows.
看她能不能把这孩子的名字提到前面
See if she can do anything to get him close to the top.
在食堂吃的
Cafeteria.
千万别吃那寿司
Stay away from the sushi.
你的手怎么了
And what happened to your hand?
被抽屉夹着了
Got stuck in a drawer.
好吧  你在戒毒
Yeah, right. You're going through withdrawal.
不是  我是疼的
No, I am going through pain.
疼痛引起呕吐
Pain causes nausea.
我来这里是跟你一起工作的
I took this job to work with you,
不是替你收拾烂摊子的
not cover your ass.
你的维柯丁
Your Vicodin.
你的解决办法就是把药给我
And your solution is to give me drugs.
-真有意思  -不是
- That's interesting. - No.
我是在收拾自己的烂摊子
Now I'm covering my ass.
趁你还没杀死那孩子前把药吃了
Take your pills before you kill this kid.
狼疮通常使用药物治疗
Lupus is normally treated with medication.
但凯斯的病情恶化太快
But in Keith's case, the disease is too advanced.
因为你撒谎
Because you lied.
因为豪斯把我儿子的命当儿戏
Because House wanted to play games with my son's life.
没法确定
There's no way to really tell what
病情发展到哪步了
progression the disease may have taken.
你说的没错
You're right.
对不起
And I'm sorry.
那我们该怎么办
So what do we do?
他需要一个新的肝脏
He needs a new liver.
移植等待名单上有一万五千人
There are over 15,000 patients on the transplant list.
那有多少人得不到新的肝脏会失血而亡
But how many are about to bleed to death unless they get a new liver?
在新泽西  大概有20个吧
In Jersey? I'd say, uh, 20.
就因为找不到供体肝脏
Two thousand patients die each year
每年有两千个病人死去
because a donor liver can't be found.
差不多是每天五个
That's almost five a day.
这么说  他完蛋了
So he's screwed.
我想想办法看吧
I'll see what I can do.
我能把自己的肝捐一部分吗
Could I donate part of my liver?
对不起  你们血型不匹配
Sorry. You're a different blood type.
-那我们只能等  -恐怕是的
- So we just wait? - I'm afraid so.
并且期待着某人死掉
And hope for someone to die.
谁是朱尔斯
Who's Jules?
豪斯医生  你应该回你的办公室去
Dr. House, you should get back to your office
朱尔斯
Jules.
-历史上没有这个人  -那是个幻觉
- There's no Jules in the history. - It was a hallucination.
-什么的幻觉  -是我家的猫
- Of what?  - Our cat.
-这有关系吗  -没有  抱歉
- Does this matter?  - No. I'm sorry.
我们会一边继续输血
We'll continue the transfusions
并继续治疗贫血和肝衰竭
and the treatment for the anemia and liver failure
一边等待捐献者
while we're waiting for a donor.
-我们还有多少时间  -没多少了
- How long can he wait?  - Not long.
我觉得这不是狼疮
I don't think this is lupus.
这就是狼疮  来吧  我们回...
It's lupus. Come on, let's just go-
你判定是狼疮的第四个依据是精神紊乱
Your fourth diagnostic criterion for lupus is psychosis.
这只是个想念自家小猫的孩子
This is just a kid missing his cat.
他被根本不存在的动物攻击了
He was being attacked by an animal that wasn't in the room.
这就是精神紊乱
That's psychosis.
精神紊乱和幻觉有本质的不同
There's a difference between psychosis and hallucination.
所以如果他见到一只虚幻的猫  那就是狼疮
So if he was imagining a fake cat, it'd be lupus,
如果是真的猫  那就不是
but since it was a real cat, it's not?
-嗑你的药去吧  -精神紊乱需要
- Take your damn pills. - Psychosis requires-
压根就没有猫
There is no cat.
朱尔斯死了
Jules is dead.
你家宠物死了  却从来没提起过
You have a dead family pet and you never mentioned it?
家族史很复杂啊
Nice family history.
家族史是关于家庭成员的
Family history's asking about family members,
是"人"才有用
meaning people related to the patient.
那猫是怎么死的
How did the cat die?
你们能让他滚吗
Can you get him outta here?
豪斯  来吧  我们...
Dr. House, come on, let's-
那猫到底怎么了
What happened to the cat?
老死了
Old age.
-她死的时候都15岁了  -什么时候
- She was 15 years old.  - When?
一个月前
About a month ago.
-这和病情有什么关系  -她睡在哪
- Does this have anything to do with- - Where'd she sleep?
-和凯斯在一起  -这不是猫过敏症
- With Keith. - This is not a cat allergy.
也不是狼疮
And it's not lupus.
朱尔斯现在在哪
Where is Jules?
我读了4年的大学
Four years of college,
4年的医学院
four at med school,
2年的实习期
two years of residency,
还经历了4年的专科医师训练  结果呢
another four of subspecialty training, and where do I end up?
在一旁光说不练
Talking instead of digging.
来吧  地都冻住了
Come on. The ground's frozen solid.
那是什么
What's that?
让开路
Out of the way!
我们拿到肝脏了  4号手术室准备
We have the liver. Prep O.R. Four.
好了  凯斯  从10开始倒数
All right, Keith, start counting backward from ten.
Ten,
nine,
eight-
手术刀
Scalpel.
停止麻醉
Stop the gases.
你他妈在干什么  豪斯
What the hell are you doing, House?
把一个16岁的孩子从终生的免疫抑制剂
Saving a 16-year-old kid from a lifetime of immunosuppressant drugs
和无法修复的手术伤疤中解救出来
and a very nasty scar.
这孩子不是狼疮性肝炎
This kid doesn't have lupoid hepatitis.
他是急性樟脑中毒
He has acute naphthalene toxicity.
樟脑  你是说卫生球
Naphthalene? Y-Y-You're talking about mothballs.
不  是白蚁
Nope. Termites.
他们制造樟脑来保护巢穴
They create naphthalene to protect their nests,
我猜他家的
which I'm assuming is rather large
白蚁已经成灾了
and inside all four walls of his bedroom at home.
你有什么依据
And your assumption is based on what?
我刚刚解剖了他家的猫
The autopsy I just conducted on his pet cat.
通知卡迪  还有保安
Call Cuddy. And Security.
你不能给他做肝脏移植
You are not removing that kid's liver.
快去
Now!
你疯了吗
Have you completely lost your mind?
我只是有点不舒服
No, but I have been feeling a little sick lately.
现在做不了手术了
There's no way we can do this surgery now.
还用你说
Ya think?
你已经让他肝衰竭了  别再害死他
You've already cost him his liver. Don't kill him too.
你就这么想给一个健康的孩子动手术啊
Why are you so eager to cut into a healthy kid?
健康  他都病入膏肓了
Healthy? He's in the toilet.
他只是需要喝点鸡汤
He just needs some chicken soup.
我去通知哈拉尼重新准备手术
I'm telling Hourani to re-scrub.
-我们必须得进行移植手术  -不行
- We're doing this transplant.  - No, you're not.
你说了  如果凯斯的症状是环境因素造成的
You said it. If Keith's symptoms had an environmental cause,
那他到这的时候就应该消失了
they would have disappeared as soon as he got here.
病情却越来越重
They've only gotten worse.
如果这儿的饭菜比雷克岛监狱好那么丁点
If the food here wasn't one step below Riker's Island,
他的情况就会好点
he would've gotten better.
-他减重了14磅  -当然
- He's lost 14 pounds-  - Sure.
原来都是饮食的问题
This is nothing but a dietary thing.
樟脑是脂溶性气体
Naphthalene is a gas, a fat-soluble gas.
病人吸入气体  就在他的脂肪细胞中囤积下来
Kid breathes it in, it gets stored in his fat cells.
没进医院时
Outside the hospital,
他的身体依靠消耗蛋白质和碳水化合物提供能量
his body burned protein and carbs for energy.
但是樟脑留在脂肪细胞中
And the naphthalene stayed in fat.
但是车祸后
But once the car accident put
他住院并开始减重
him in the hospital and he started losing weight,
他的身体只能从别处获得能量
his body had to get its energy somewhere else.
于是开始燃烧脂肪
It started to burn fat.
闸门打开了
The floodgates opened.
毒气进入他的循环系统
The poison poured into his system.
那你是说离开毒源反而害了他吗
So getting away from the poison is what poisoned him?
不让他吃他爸做的肉馅饼才害了他
Getting away from his dad's meat loaf is what's killing him.
你准备好给我解释阻止手术的原因了吗
You wanna explain to me why you stopped the surgery?
我的天呐
Oh, my God! My God.
-我要告你  -嘿
- I want him locked up! - Hey.!
不要激动
Take it easy.
你家的猫不是老死的
Your cat did not die of old age.
它是死于樟脑中毒引发的
It died of massive internal bleeding and acute liver failure...
大面积内出血和急性肝衰竭
caused by naphthalene poisoning.
和你儿子的病因完全一样
The exact same thing your son has.
你对我撒谎  你搅黄我儿子的手术
You lie to me, you mess up my son's surgery,
现在你还指望我会相信你吗
and now you expect me to trust you?
给我24个小时
Give me 24 hours.
我们给你儿子足够的卡路里
We'll pump your son full of calories-
那个肝脏已经给别人了
That liver is going to somebody right now.
我们要做手术
We're doing that surgery.
你要做了  就等于杀了四个孩子的母亲
You do the surgery, you'll be killing a mother of four.
三个孩子的父亲
Father of three.
-我猜的  -现在也是吗
- I was guessing. - Like you are now?
樟脑中毒是我们
Naphthalene poisoning is the best explanation
能做出的最合理的诊断
we have for what's wrong with your son.
它能解释内出血
It explains the internal bleeding,
溶血性贫血和肝衰竭的原因
the hemolytic anemia, the liver failure.
下面的故事也就可想而知了
It also predicts what'll happen next.
如果你执意做手术
If you do the surgery,
他要被扔在手术台上14个小时
he's gonna lay on that table for 14 hours...
继而消耗更多的脂肪
while his body continues to
排放出更多的毒素
burn fat and release poison into his system.
不管怎样  我帮你个忙
Either way, I did you a favor.
他现在醒了  去和他临终道别吧
He's awake now. You've got a chance to say good-bye.
我认为你应该相信豪斯医生
I think you should trust Dr. House.
把肝脏让给别人
Give the liver to the other guy.
小心
Watch out.
凝血酶比值下降  红细胞数量上升
I.N.R.'s down and his red count is climbing.
你的决定是对的
Means you made the right call.
他的肝功能在恢复  他没事了
His liver is healing. He's gonna be just fine.
你坚持了一周
You made it a week.
还赢了我的奖励
And won my prize.
-祝贺你  -卡迪是个笨蛋
- Congratulations. - Cuddy's a sucker.
其实只要两周不出门诊就行
I would've done it for two weeks off.
是啊  小菜一碟
Yeah, it was a piece of cake.
有什么收获吗
You learn anything?
有
Yeah.
我是个瘾君子
I'm an addict.
好吧
Okay.
我不会戒药的
I'm not stopping.
有不少戒药项目
There are programs.
卡迪会给你时间
Cuddy would give you the time.
你能找到新方法来抑制疼痛
You could get on a different pain management regimen.
我不需要戒药
I don't need to stop.
你刚说
You just said-
我说我是个瘾君子  可没说这是问题
I said I was an addict. I didn't say I had a problem.
我花钱买药  自己做饭  我能工作
I pay my bills. I make my meals. I function.
这就是你想要的  你都没什么朋友
Is that all you want? You have no relationships.
我不想要朋友
I don't want any relationships.
你故意疏远别人
You alienate people.
从三岁开始我就这样了
I've been alienating people since I was three.
行了  别这样
Oh, come on! Drop it.
你不觉得你已经变了吗
You don't think you've changed in the last few years?
当然
Well, of course I have.
我老了  头发稀疏了
I've- I've gotten older, my hair's got thinner.
有时我觉得无聊  有时我觉得孤独
Sometimes I'm bored. Sometimes I'm lonely.
有时我质疑活着的价值
Sometimes I wonder what it all means.
不  我见证了一切
No, I was there.
你不只是变老了那么简单
You are not just a regular guy who's getting older.
你变了  你痛苦异常  不敢面对自己
You've changed. You're miserable, and you're afraid to face yourself.
我当然变了
Of course I've changed!
都是因为腿吗
And everything's the leg?
和药没有关系吗  他们对你毫无作用吗
Nothing's the pills? They haven't done a thing to you?
他们让我静心工作
They let me do my job.
让我远离疼痛
And they take away my pain.
谈得怎么样
How'd it go?
他承认他对麻醉剂上瘾
He admitted he's addicted to the narcotics.
向你承认只是
Well, admitting you have a problem
-第一步  -他说这不是问题
- is the first  - And he says it's not a problem.
也许真不是问题
Maybe it's not.
我不知道
What do I know?
你打算怎么办
What are you gonna do?
什么都不干  够焦头烂额的了
Nothing. Done enough damage.
最好别让他知道这是你的主意
Better hope he never finds out that that was your idea.
他不会信的
He'd never believe it.